<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home Dashboard Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Running a household is hard work. Organization is not easy to achieve or maintain and time is short. We have tried many calendar and planning systems. Digital calendars provided the greatest benefit due to their integration with phones and instantaneous sync between family members. One downside is the lack of a single, large display that a traditional paper calendar might provide. This presented an opportunity to solve a real problem with a digital dashboard. The primary goal was to display the calendar on a screen where all family members could see it. Other possible benfits included the ability to display a todo list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/conn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/conn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;making-connections&#34;&gt;Making Connections&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;What is a TCP Connection?&amp;rsquo; This seemingly simple question led to a lot of digging and a lot of learning. I&amp;rsquo;ve danced around networking for a long time. Like many (most?) software developers, networking is sometimes a twist, often a struggle, and never the point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-hate-networking&#34;&gt;I Hate Networking&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just kidding. I don&amp;rsquo;t inherently dislike networking. It&amp;rsquo;s actually sort of fascinating and beautiful. But it&amp;rsquo;s also mysterious. Counterintuitive. Hidden. Daunting. I received a rushed intro on TCP and other networking concepts early in my journey. TCP got brief attention - enough to grasp the basic idea - and little more. I saw a diagram that looked like this:&#xA;![[diagram.jpg]]&#xA;(Credit: AI Slop. Check out that spelling&amp;hellip;!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About me&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
