<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on NWLR</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on NWLR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:13:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making Connections</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-10-16-making-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:13:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-10-16-making-connections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;What is a TCP Connection?&amp;rsquo; This seemingly simple question led to a lot of digging and a lot of learning. I&amp;rsquo;ve danced around networking for a long time. Like many (most?) software developers, networking is sometimes a twist, often a struggle, and never the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mystery&#34;&gt;Mystery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t inherently dislike networking. It&amp;rsquo;s actually sort of fascinating and beautiful. But it&amp;rsquo;s also mysterious. Counterintuitive. Hidden. Daunting. I received a rushed intro on TCP and other networking concepts early in my journey. TCP got brief attention - enough to grasp the basic idea - and little more. I saw a diagram that looked like this:
![[./unnamed.jpg]]
(Credit: AI Slop. Check out that spelling&amp;hellip;!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With Chaos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-09-22-dealing-with-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 19:13:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-09-22-dealing-with-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chaos&#34;&gt;Chaos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Applebee&amp;rsquo;s on Sunday afternoon. Not by choice. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t willingly choose to eat there. Someone I love had a gift card. There are two of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A family of reaches the entrance at the same time as we do. The father and I play leap frog with the doors. We joke about it a little bit and he seems nice enough. His wife has a much different demeantor. She looks at me suspiciously, as if my goal is to beat them to the front of the line. I&amp;rsquo;m tired, in no rush, and not particularly interested in eating the food. They are served first and find a seat at a hightop near the bar. We continue to wait for a few more minutes. As I casually scan the room the wife is again looking at me. She seems pleased to be sitting, but perhaps fighting feelings of guilt? that she was seated first. I&amp;rsquo;m stumped by her continued engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Dashboard Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-08-16-home-dashboard-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-08-16-home-dashboard-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a household is hard work. Organization is not easy to achieve or maintain and time is short. We have tried many calendar and planning systems. Digital calendars provided the greatest benefit due to their integration with phones and instantaneous sync between family members. One downside is the lack of a single, large display that a traditional paper calendar might provide. This presented an opportunity to solve a real problem with a digital dashboard. The primary goal was to display the calendar on a screen where all family members could see it. Other possible benfits included the ability to display a todo list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
